<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>My Thoughts</title>
    <link>https://yogeshdhamija.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on My Thoughts</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 31 Aug 2020 04:00:48 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="https://yogeshdhamija.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    
        <item>
        <title>Recipe: Cinnamon Daliya</title>
        <link>https://yogeshdhamija.github.io/recipes/cinnamon-dalia/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 31 Aug 2020 04:00:48 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://yogeshdhamija.github.io/recipes/cinnamon-dalia/</guid>
        <description>My Thoughts https://yogeshdhamija.github.io/recipes/cinnamon-dalia/ -&lt;p&gt;~2 servings&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Into a pot on stove:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
1 tablespoon butter&lt;br&gt;
0.5 cup daliya (cracked wheat)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stir constantly.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;When browned:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
1.25 cup water&lt;br&gt;
2.11 cup (0.5 liter) milk&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stir constantly.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;When reduced and daliya is cooked:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
1 teaspoon daalchini (cinnamon) powder&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;??? honey&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;??? sliced almonds&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
- https://yogeshdhamija.github.io/recipes/cinnamon-dalia/ - </description>
        </item>
    
    
    
        <item>
        <title>Recipe: Chai</title>
        <link>https://yogeshdhamija.github.io/recipes/chai/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jul 2020 18:52:26 -0500</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://yogeshdhamija.github.io/recipes/chai/</guid>
        <description>My Thoughts https://yogeshdhamija.github.io/recipes/chai/ -&lt;p&gt;~4 servings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Into a large pot on stove:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
3 cups water&lt;br&gt;
5 tablespoons Assam loose leaf black tea &lt;br&gt;
1 inch ginger (adhrak) sliced&lt;br&gt;
10 cloves (laung)&lt;br&gt;
15 green cardamom pods (elaichi)&lt;br&gt;
2 inch cinnamon (daalchini) stick&lt;br&gt;
15 black peppercorns&lt;br&gt;
5 star anises&lt;br&gt;
0.5 teaspoon fennel seeds (saumph)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;When at a low boil:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Cover pot&lt;br&gt;
Lower heat to simmer and let it sit&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;After at least 10 minutes:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
3 cups milk&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@harshadkulkarni/the-perfect-indian-masala-chai-4e98fabf42ec&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;The Perfect Indian Masala Chai&amp;rdquo;, Medium article by Harshad Kulkarni&lt;/a&gt;, with modifications.&lt;br&gt;
Image attribution: &lt;a href=&#34;https://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:Kullad_chai.jpg&#34;&gt;by Thecuriouseye, on Wikimedia Commons&lt;/a&gt;. Licence: &lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0&#34;&gt;CC BY-SA&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
- https://yogeshdhamija.github.io/recipes/chai/ - </description>
        </item>
    
    
    
        <item>
        <title>Recipe: Chole</title>
        <link>https://yogeshdhamija.github.io/recipes/chole/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jul 2020 22:28:46 -0500</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://yogeshdhamija.github.io/recipes/chole/</guid>
        <description>My Thoughts https://yogeshdhamija.github.io/recipes/chole/ -&lt;p&gt;~5 servings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Into a pot on stove:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
3 cups white chickpeas soaked overnight&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;??? cups water&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;
3 inch cinnamon stick&lt;br&gt;
15 cardamom pods (elaichi)&lt;br&gt;
1.5 bay leaf&lt;br&gt;
1.5 teaspoon ginger paste&lt;br&gt;
0.5 teaspoon baking soda&lt;br&gt;
1.5 teaspoon salt&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;After chickpeas cooked al dente:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Strain out water and save it&lt;br&gt;
Remove cinnamon, cardamom pods, bay leaves from chickpeas&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Into a large pan on stove:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
6 tablespoon oil&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;When hot:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
1.5 large onion chopped&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;When brown:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
6 green chillies slit&lt;br&gt;
5.25 medium-sized tomato chopped&lt;br&gt;
1.5 teaspoon ginger chopped&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;When soft and mushy:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
all the chickpeas obtained previously&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;After flavours combine (couple minutes):&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
3 teaspoon cumin powder (jira)&lt;br&gt;
3 teaspoon coriander powder (dhaniya)&lt;br&gt;
1.5 teaspoon cayenne (laal mirch)&lt;br&gt;
3 teaspoon garam masaala&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;??? teaspoon turmeric (haldi)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;??? lemon squeezed&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;After mixing:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
until slightly too wet: add stock obtained previously, or water if there&amp;rsquo;s not enough&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reduce until desired consistency&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Add salt to taste&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.vegrecipesofindia.com/amritsari-chole-recipe/&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Amritsari Chole&amp;rdquo;, by Dassana Amit&lt;/a&gt;, with modifications.
Image attribution: &lt;a href=&#34;https://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:Chole_Masala_India.jpg&#34;&gt;by Divya Kudua, on Wikimedia Commons&lt;/a&gt;. Licence: &lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/2.0&#34;&gt;CC BY&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
- https://yogeshdhamija.github.io/recipes/chole/ - </description>
        </item>
    
    
    
        <item>
        <title>CV</title>
        <link>https://yogeshdhamija.github.io/cv/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jun 2020 17:09:04 -0500</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://yogeshdhamija.github.io/cv/</guid>
        <description>My Thoughts https://yogeshdhamija.github.io/cv/ -
&lt;object data=&#34;/Yogesh Dhamija - CV.pdf&#34; type=&#34;application/pdf&#34; width=&#34;100%&#34; height=&#34;1129px&#34; style=&#34;position:relative; top:-150px; margin-bottom:-150px;&#34;&gt;
    &lt;embed src=&#34;https://yogeshdhamija.github.io/Yogesh Dhamija - CV.pdf&#34;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;This browser does not support PDFs. Please download the PDF to view it: &lt;a href=&#34;https://yogeshdhamija.github.io/Yogesh Dhamija - CV.pdf&#34;&gt;Download PDF&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/embed&gt;
&lt;/object&gt;
- https://yogeshdhamija.github.io/cv/ - </description>
        </item>
    
    
    
        <item>
        <title>Recipe: Tadka</title>
        <link>https://yogeshdhamija.github.io/recipes/tadka/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jun 2020 22:59:28 -0400</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://yogeshdhamija.github.io/recipes/tadka/</guid>
        <description>My Thoughts https://yogeshdhamija.github.io/recipes/tadka/ -&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Into a pan on stove:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
1 tablespoon Olive Oil&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;When warm:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
1/2 teaspoon Cumin seeds (jira)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;When brown:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
1 cups diced Onion&lt;br&gt;
2&amp;quot; piece of root of Ginger (adrak), diced&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;When brown:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
0.5 cups diced Tomato&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;??? Chilli Pepper&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lower temp, then:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
2 teaspoon coriander powder (dhaniya)&lt;br&gt;
1/2 teaspoon garam masaala&lt;br&gt;
2 teaspoon cayenne (laal mirch)&lt;br&gt;
1/2 teaspoon salt&lt;br&gt;
1/2 teaspoon turmeric (haldi)&lt;br&gt;
Acid (lemon/lime juice)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Higher temp and mix. Add water if too dry.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
- https://yogeshdhamija.github.io/recipes/tadka/ - </description>
        </item>
    
    
    
        <item>
        <title>Story: Mayflies</title>
        <link>https://yogeshdhamija.github.io/writing/mayflies/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jun 2020 15:22:34 -0500</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://yogeshdhamija.github.io/writing/mayflies/</guid>
        <description>My Thoughts https://yogeshdhamija.github.io/writing/mayflies/ -&lt;p&gt;The crowd went silent when the human entered the bar. You didn&amp;rsquo;t see many of their kind here. He grumbled, uncomfortable for the attention, walked up to the counter and signalled for a mug.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s when the whispers started. Mayfly. Young one. The walking dead. He was happy to down his ale.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You see, this wasn&amp;rsquo;t your average bar. This was a speakeasy, one of the few scattered across the world where the elves and the dwarves shared a drink. Where the seraphim flirted with yokai, while fae fluttered from table to table. Where the orcs played chess at their own table, practically drowning themselves in ale. Where seldom a human showed his face.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They aren&amp;rsquo;t rare, of course, humans. No, quite the opposite. They simply didn&amp;rsquo;t live long enough. Speakeasies are illegal, you see &amp;ndash; no self respecting elf could be seen drinking with a dwarf, or dare I say, an orc &amp;ndash; so they&amp;rsquo;re not exactly advertised. The humans who helped found these establishments had long since died. They&amp;rsquo;re mayflies, alive just barely long enough to be young, and dead practically as they learned to walk. The new humans since simply hadn&amp;rsquo;t heard of the place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;There you are, Arthur! It&amp;rsquo;s been a long time since I saw you last!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The bar quieted once again as she walked in. Drea, high elf, and uncontested beauty. Many pairs of eyes tracked her as she comfortably made her way to the counter, where the human was nursing his second drink.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Has it been that long? Seems like only yesterday,&amp;rdquo; he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A second passed before he cracked a smile.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;But it is nice to see you again, Drea, after all these years. I was beginning to get bored.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She laughed, embraced him, and for a while they simply enjoyed each other, rocking slightly as they hugged.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The chatter in the bar changed as the pair caught up. The beautiful, stately high elf laughing as the human told some story, snorting as the ale went up her nose. She was clearly smitten, and many of the larger orcs and stronger dwarves, now more than a little intoxicated, took exception to such a lady falling for a human.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;No!&amp;rdquo; she was saying between laughing spurts, &amp;ldquo;Surely Matt told you it was a bad idea!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Was it, though? I&amp;rsquo;m telling you, my arms are pretty long, and the River doesn&amp;rsquo;t have any&amp;ndash; Ah, can I help you gentlemen?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A dwarf had approached the counter in the company of a rather large orc, both wearing faces that shouted &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m stricken by her beauty, but I don&amp;rsquo;t want her to know it.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Nae, nae youngster,&amp;rdquo; said the dwarf. &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;d more like if ye lady friend here&amp;rsquo;d care for another drink! So&amp;rsquo;thing stronger, maybe, with some flavor!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Aye,&amp;rdquo; the orc boomed, &amp;ldquo;something stronger!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Arthur quietly admitted to himself, he was impressed with the orc&amp;rsquo;s bulging muscles as he flexed. Drea, apparently, wasn&amp;rsquo;t.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Oh quiet yourselves, my friends. I&amp;rsquo;m afraid you&amp;rsquo;ll have to drink with each other. I am quite taken.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A fist slammed hard on the counter, &amp;ldquo;By the human?! What can this young thing do that I can&amp;rsquo;t! I can lift a mountain!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Arthur believed him. He tapped the orc on the shoulder to get his attention, and felt the rock of his muscle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Aye, my friend,&amp;rdquo; he said, &amp;ldquo;taken by me. I&amp;rsquo;m sure there are others here that would be more receptive of your charm?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Nae,&amp;rdquo; said the dwarf, &amp;ldquo;I wan&#39; te know what makes ye better than us who been buildin&#39; when ye gran&amp;rsquo;father still be suckling milk!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Ah but we can so easily tell you,&amp;rdquo; said Drea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Arthur wasn&amp;rsquo;t so sure. &amp;ldquo;We can?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Sure, sure! Please continue your story.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ah, now he saw where she was going with this. He swigged his ale and cleared his throat, warming back up to the story.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Aye, so there I was, at the top of the cliff by the bank of the Gaiden&amp;rsquo;s Blood River with my friend Matt. We were looking at the River down below. I&amp;rsquo;ve been swimming in it, and it&amp;rsquo;s gorgeous. It&amp;rsquo;s exactly the perfect temperature and it&amp;rsquo;s so deep and wide you can swim for hours. I really did feel like a swim&amp;ndash; it was getting rather boring up top.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eyes started widening as Redbeard, and Grukk began to realize where this was going. Gaiden&amp;rsquo;s Blood River, as you probably know, is the largest river in the world. As the story goes, when the blood rushed out from the god Gaiden&amp;rsquo;s wound, the force of it cut such a deep swathe in the earth that its banks are huge cliffs. How the River changed from blood to water is a story for another time, but the cliffs are so high that a dive would surely kill even the most sturdy dwarf.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Surely he didn&amp;rsquo;t.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Surely ye didn&amp;rsquo;t&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Jump? Of course not! I&amp;rsquo;ve no wish for death. See, we have these things called parachutes &amp;ndash; large cuts of fabric, as large as the largest dining table in the largest hall, that catch the air and slow your fall. But I didn&amp;rsquo;t have a parachute.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eyes widened again. Such an invention didn&amp;rsquo;t exist among the dwarves or the orcs, and neither Redbeard nor Grukk could think of a more reckless, irresponsible, unsafe thing to do than to fall freely from the sky with nothing but fabric to stop you. Didn&amp;rsquo;t this human have better things to do?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I didn&amp;rsquo;t have a parachute&amp;ndash;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The pair sighed in relief.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;&amp;ndash;but our tents were made of the same fabric, so I told Matt to hold my beer, and I cut the damn things into wings from my wrists to my ankles. See, I&amp;rsquo;ve got pretty long arms, and I figure my wingspan would be enough to catch enough air that I could glide down to the River.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At this point, both sets of eyes were as wide as dinner plates, and Drea was quite amused by the rapt attention with which they were absorbed. She could hardly blame them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;An&#39; it worked?&amp;rdquo; ventured Redbeard the dwarf. Drea, too, was curious.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Worked?! My friend, it was amazing! It felt like flying! I didn&amp;rsquo;t even bother swimming! Soon as I landed, I climbed the two-day path back up the cliff and I jumped again!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Drea was the first to break the silence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;You really are something, aren&amp;rsquo;t you, Arthur.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Human,&amp;rdquo; said the orc, &amp;ldquo;you are lucky to be alive. What drove you to such madness? Why threaten your life?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Aye. Ar&#39; ye mad, ye dumb bastard?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;No, not mad. Just bored.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Bored?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Neither man had ever heard of the term. It must have been some sort of madness to drive a human &amp;ndash; already with so short a life &amp;ndash; to commit to such a danger so readily. They glanced blankly at each other, clearly confused.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;What&amp;rsquo;s bored?&amp;rdquo; they said in unison.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;If I may,&amp;rdquo; said Drea. &amp;ldquo;I can explain.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Arthur gestured for her to go ahead, as he drank his ale.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;You see, humans, and especially Arthur here, occasionally enter a state of mind that drives them to do ridiculous things. I daresay it&amp;rsquo;s a kind of madness, but we&amp;rsquo;ve been arguing about that for ages. There is a very interesting cause to this madness to which all humans succumb.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She waited a beat, and watched as both men were swallowing nervously.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s caused by a lack of threats in their immediate environment. Humans crave threats, you see. Threats to overcome. And that is why, gentlemen, I stand by his side over yours.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thus leaving both men impressed, Drea grabbed Arthur by the arm, and they walked out of the bar together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;You are extraordinary, you know,&amp;rdquo; she said, &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m very glad I met you. You must&amp;rsquo;ve been mad to approach one such as me, a high elf, so many years ago.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He kissed her then, smiled, and said &amp;ldquo;No, not mad, my dear. Just bored.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
- https://yogeshdhamija.github.io/writing/mayflies/ - </description>
        </item>
    
    
    
        <item>
        <title>Story: Mutiny</title>
        <link>https://yogeshdhamija.github.io/writing/mutiny/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jun 2020 15:22:34 -0500</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://yogeshdhamija.github.io/writing/mutiny/</guid>
        <description>My Thoughts https://yogeshdhamija.github.io/writing/mutiny/ -&lt;p&gt;They&amp;rsquo;re all dumb as rocks. Basalt. They&amp;rsquo;re dumb as basalt. We had a budget of 160,000. That left us with less than 5,000 buffer after we dropped off 20 metric crap-tonnes of basalt and paid the ridiculous taxes to the various governments. That&amp;rsquo;s even after all my tricks. 5,000.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then some ship that hasn&amp;rsquo;t seen a car-wash in at least a century or two rolls around and asks for some money because of some supernova on some planet. It&amp;rsquo;s a scam! Anyone with two brain-cells to rub together and a Dr. Seuss poem for an education could figure that out! Oh, am I burned to a crisp? No? Then no bloody supernova! But nooooooo, they lay on some “we&amp;rsquo;re the last of our species” and “help me obi wan kenobi you&amp;rsquo;re my only hope” and all of a sudden our basalt of a captain gives them 10,000! And then he has the nerve to shrug at me and says “figure it out, Bob.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well I told ol&#39; Space Brad to help me and I&amp;rsquo;d give him a vacation and a fish, and he got right on board (after he reamed me for calling him Space Brad). So now our captain can go dig up for more basalt while I sell his fancy nacell collection to make up for the money. He&amp;rsquo;s tied up in the brig now. Go get his nacells or imma tell Space Brad to do your face in. And bring beer.&lt;/p&gt;
- https://yogeshdhamija.github.io/writing/mutiny/ - </description>
        </item>
    
    
    
        <item>
        <title>Story: Redress</title>
        <link>https://yogeshdhamija.github.io/writing/redress/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jun 2020 15:22:34 -0500</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://yogeshdhamija.github.io/writing/redress/</guid>
        <description>My Thoughts https://yogeshdhamija.github.io/writing/redress/ -&lt;h2 id=&#34;based-on-the-writing-prompt&#34;&gt;Based on the Writing Prompt:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You are the guardian of everything that has ever been lost. Anyone may come to you to reclaim what they have lost, but you require them to offer something of significant worth to take its place in your collection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;redress&#34;&gt;Redress&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Blessings my brethren readily provide. They shower them.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;I do not like to bless.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;For Ares builds leaders to rule and preside, and seraphim&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Are born from her caress.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;But bones bear my mark. With suicide the price so grim,&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Little is worth redress.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When the sinew had rotted away, it was the mark that kept the skeleton hand clutched around the ledger. When the eyes had receded into their holes, and maggots had long since eaten the tongue, it was the mark that allowed the corpse to read.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And thank the Gods it did read, for I did not come for naught.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It read to me the prayer. The prayer to the Old Gods. The prayer I had recited every morning as a child in school. The prayer I had come to despise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ares, Mercury, Mahesh, Osiris. I know all their prayers by heart. But the last one is new. The last one, I&amp;rsquo;d memorized only recently. The last one, I&amp;rsquo;d only found in the oldest books, written in arcane script, and burned by the thousands.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From its book, it read to me the prayer to the Oldest God.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I waited for the prayer to end. On the ground I sat, and I waited. I felt the spiders re-building their webs, the webs I&amp;rsquo;d broken when I&amp;rsquo;d entered. I felt them on my hands and my hair, but I did not interrupt them. I listened to the prayer, and I waited.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“What have you lost?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even now, having come so far, having spurned all that the world offered me, I felt hesitation. I felt it claw at my mind, desperately pleading for me to reconsider. I felt it in my spine as it grew cold and my hair stood on end. I felt it in my chest as my heart shriveled up and died. And I smiled.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I&amp;rsquo;ve lost my khushi.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It did not need explanation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Will you pay the price?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The hesitation was no more. I had killed it. Now there was only desperation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Yes.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And then I saw her in the mist. Adrenaline nulled my hearing. Yearning broke my sense of time. I felt my chest swell as it had only done once before. My feet took me to her, and my hands brought her to me, and as I held her I realized I was weeping.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She is here. She is here. And she, too, is weeping.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Hush now,” I told her, “there is a boat outside this cave. It will take you home.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It took more than I had to break from her embrace. My breathing betrayed my fear, and my heart fluttered its dissent, but my chest held high as I sat on the throne.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I grabbed the ledger from the old guardian, and I claimed its mark for myself, and I smiled. For the first time in years, I truly smiled.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Go now,” I said, “your mother needs you.”&lt;/p&gt;
- https://yogeshdhamija.github.io/writing/redress/ - </description>
        </item>
    
    
    
        <item>
        <title>Story: The Butterfly</title>
        <link>https://yogeshdhamija.github.io/writing/butterfly/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jun 2020 15:22:34 -0500</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://yogeshdhamija.github.io/writing/butterfly/</guid>
        <description>My Thoughts https://yogeshdhamija.github.io/writing/butterfly/ -&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rip&amp;hellip; beep.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Her hands were moving almost of their own accord. Numb. Routine. No thinking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rip&amp;hellip; beep.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two weeks. It had been two weeks now. Almost finished.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rip&amp;hellip; beep.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An air hostess&amp;ndash; that&amp;rsquo;s all she&amp;rsquo;d ever been. She didn&amp;rsquo;t do the important things, the big things, like cure cancer or rescue people from burning buildings. But she helped. Little things. She smiled at people on the street. She helped the elderly cross the road. Last month, she had spent every day after work talking to John at the orphanage. An angry little kid, that one, but she knew he just needed someone to talk to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Henry Jones was his name, the last man she smiled at on the street. He walked straight to an AA meeting after. Good thing, too, because he was this close to heading home instead that day, and his wife would have shown him the papers she had finally gotten back from her lawyer. Well, her mother&amp;rsquo;s lawyer, to be more accurate. She couldn&amp;rsquo;t afford it on her own, not with Henry&amp;rsquo;s drinking. It would&amp;rsquo;ve killed him. They would&amp;rsquo;ve found him on the ground next to that building on 34th street. Long way down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She couldn&amp;rsquo;t bring herself to smile at people anymore. She had brushed past a really skinny guy a couple of days ago, sunken eyes and scars on his arms. They found Reg the next day in a rundown apartment, a needle in his arm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rip&amp;hellip; beep.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She should&amp;rsquo;ve smiled.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;John was a difficult fourteen year old. Ran away three times from the orphanage. They made fun of him for not being so bright because he got caught every time within a few days. He didn&amp;rsquo;t do well in school either. Punched Aron in the face when he made fun of him for it. Always angry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She got him ice cream. Häagen Daz mango sorbet&amp;ndash; now his favorite. He developed a real respect for her. His first real friend, older though she was. He didn&amp;rsquo;t know she knew, of course, and he wasn&amp;rsquo;t the type to say thank you. But once in a while, when he thought she was too busy enjoying her own ice cream to notice (she was more of a vanilla gal), he&amp;rsquo;d stare at her with wet in his eyes. He didn&amp;rsquo;t think she noticed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They went every day to that ice cream store on 29th, at the corner of Grand street. She didn&amp;rsquo;t have ice cream every day, of course. Not with that air hostess figure to keep. But John&amp;rsquo;s growing musculature proved that it did him no harm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a good thing she saved him from that life. Prison was where he&amp;rsquo;d end up. Jersey State Prison, to be exact. Assault and battery. But now he was really trying to turn his life around.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In twelve years, he&amp;rsquo;d be a research intern at MIT. In fourteen, he&amp;rsquo;d be the lead scientist to find a viable treatment for dementia. And they had made fun of him for not being bright. But she knew.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She always knows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rip&amp;hellip; beep.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She didn&amp;rsquo;t do anything big. She left that to that guy in Gotham.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rip&amp;hellip; beep.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then again, there was that bolt she had loosened once.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rip&amp;hellip; beep.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That pretty redhead would&amp;rsquo;ve been raped and murdered. Brutal. He would&amp;rsquo;ve killed hundreds the next day. Good with explosives, he was, a chemistry major.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rip&amp;hellip; beep.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But the support beam fell on them. A loose bolt. The girl died instantly, him the next day. A tragedy, the paper had said. But she knew.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rip&amp;hellip; beep.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No. Stop. No thinking. It was almost over.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Butterfly, she liked to call herself back in the early days. Like a superhero. It made her want to wear a cape. She&amp;rsquo;d go out every day, find the littlest things she could do that would have the biggest positive impact. She saved a man&amp;rsquo;s life, years before it was under threat, by slipping a condom in his bag. She stopped suicides every day by shaking a hand, or giving a high five.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She&amp;rsquo;d be smiling in her sleep every night.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But it got tougher. She saved eight hundred and twelve lives once, by taking two.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then it got tougher. She saved six, by taking one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then it got painful. She saved the woman that would eradicate the flu, a disease killing millions each year. But she had to kill a family of four. Innocent children.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rip&amp;hellip; beep.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She didn&amp;rsquo;t call herself the Butterfly anymore. She didn&amp;rsquo;t smile at night.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rip&amp;hellip; beep.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It had been two weeks since she became sure. It was either the towers, or the white house. There was no other way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rip&amp;hellip; beep.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was better this way. She knew that. She had seen it. The drone strikes would stay on foreign soil, not here. The wars would be shorter. There would be no draft.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rip&amp;hellip; beep.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Next,” she called. “Next!”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Her voice was hoarse. Her tone was callous.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That was the last one. The line had ended. They had all boarded. She waited for a couple more minutes. She contemplated just leaving. She could walk down the corridor and survive. She could save more lives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She sighed. No. No thinking. It was too much. She packed up her purse, inserted the ticket stubs into their proper slot, locked the drawer, and boarded the plane. United Airlines flight 93, bound to San Francisco. It wouldn&amp;rsquo;t get there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But it wouldn&amp;rsquo;t reach D.C. either. She&amp;rsquo;d made sure of it. She&amp;rsquo;d spilled that coffee that ensured that those people would be on the flight. They&amp;rsquo;d stop it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That coffee that damned so many others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She strapped herself in, and took a look at her watch. Eight o&amp;rsquo;clock in the morning, Tuesday, September the 11th, 2001.&lt;/p&gt;
- https://yogeshdhamija.github.io/writing/butterfly/ - </description>
        </item>
    
    
  </channel>
</rss> 