<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>sci-fi on My Thoughts</title>
    <link>https://yogeshdhamija.github.io/tags/sci-fi/</link>
    <description>Recent content in sci-fi on My Thoughts</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 24 Jun 2020 15:22:34 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://yogeshdhamija.github.io/tags/sci-fi/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Story: Mayflies</title>
      <link>https://yogeshdhamija.github.io/writing/mayflies/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jun 2020 15:22:34 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yogeshdhamija.github.io/writing/mayflies/</guid>
      <description>The crowd went silent when the human entered the bar. You didn&amp;rsquo;t see many of their kind here. He grumbled, uncomfortable for the attention, walked up to the counter and signalled for a mug.
That&amp;rsquo;s when the whispers started. Mayfly. Young one. The walking dead. He was happy to down his ale.
You see, this wasn&amp;rsquo;t your average bar. This was a speakeasy, one of the few scattered across the world where the elves and the dwarves shared a drink.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Story: Mutiny</title>
      <link>https://yogeshdhamija.github.io/writing/mutiny/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jun 2020 15:22:34 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yogeshdhamija.github.io/writing/mutiny/</guid>
      <description>They&amp;rsquo;re all dumb as rocks. Basalt. They&amp;rsquo;re dumb as basalt. We had a budget of 160,000. That left us with less than 5,000 buffer after we dropped off 20 metric crap-tonnes of basalt and paid the ridiculous taxes to the various governments. That&amp;rsquo;s even after all my tricks. 5,000.
Then some ship that hasn&amp;rsquo;t seen a car-wash in at least a century or two rolls around and asks for some money because of some supernova on some planet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Story: Redress</title>
      <link>https://yogeshdhamija.github.io/writing/redress/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jun 2020 15:22:34 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yogeshdhamija.github.io/writing/redress/</guid>
      <description>Based on the Writing Prompt: You are the guardian of everything that has ever been lost. Anyone may come to you to reclaim what they have lost, but you require them to offer something of significant worth to take its place in your collection.
Redress  Blessings my brethren readily provide. They shower them.
I do not like to bless.
For Ares builds leaders to rule and preside, and seraphim</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Story: The Butterfly</title>
      <link>https://yogeshdhamija.github.io/writing/butterfly/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jun 2020 15:22:34 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yogeshdhamija.github.io/writing/butterfly/</guid>
      <description>Rip&amp;hellip; beep.
Her hands were moving almost of their own accord. Numb. Routine. No thinking.
Rip&amp;hellip; beep.
Two weeks. It had been two weeks now. Almost finished.
Rip&amp;hellip; beep.
An air hostess&amp;ndash; that&amp;rsquo;s all she&amp;rsquo;d ever been. She didn&amp;rsquo;t do the important things, the big things, like cure cancer or rescue people from burning buildings. But she helped. Little things. She smiled at people on the street. She helped the elderly cross the road.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
